Simon Bihel

simonbihel.me github.com/sbihel

SKILLS

Rust One of my main interests, I have four years of experience working with it in different contexts, from libraries and web services to bindings in various languages.

Infrastructure One of my main responsibilities, I have experience working on internal infrastructure as well as working in customers' environments.

Digital Identity I have been working in this domain for four years, ranging from working and implementing standards to designing solutions.

EXPERIENCE

SpruceID(Remote) London, United-KingdomPrincipal Software Engineer, Head of InfrastructureMarch 2023 - PresentSenior Software Engineer, Infrastructure LeadApril 2022 - March 2023

Software Engineer

- Joined as the second employee and worked on most projects over the years.
- Development: worked on most libraries and services. Mostly in Rust but generated bindings for other languages. Also worked on web and mobile apps.
- Standards: participated in the implementation of new standards (e.g. Verifiable Credentials, OID4VC, ISO mDL, Sign-In with Ethereum).
- Infrastructure: single person responsible for it, I provided direction and did most of the implementation.
- DevOps: managed services deployments, CI/CD pipelines, and monitoring.
- Architecture: contributed to infrastructure and software architecture discussions.
- Compliance: worked on the infrastructure side of SOC2.
- Management: up to 7 direct reports at a time, I was also part of the leadership team.

Nexmo (Vonage)

London, United-Kingdom

September 2020 - April 2022

simon@simonbihel.me

Software Development Engineer in Test

November 2018 - October 2020

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Testing: maintenance of the test suite (e.g. \ abstraction \ and \ generation \ of \ tests, \ parallelisation)}.$
- Monitoring: facilitate incident impact measurement, track API usage, alerting (pushed for on-call).
- Investigations: understanding test failures or abnormal behaviours across the services.
- Development: built a rating engine, refactored cluster management, various internal changes in services.
- DevOps: AWS migration, maintenance of on-demand test environments (e.g. dockerise services, debugging).

KTH Stockholm, Sweden
Research Intern February 2018 – June 2018

KAIST Daejeon, South-Korea
Research Intern March 2017 – August 2017

IRISA & INRIA

Rennes, France
Research Intern

May 2016 - July 2016

EDUCATION

University of Rennes 1 & ÉNS Rennes

Rennes, France

BSc & MSc in Computer Science, research track

2013 - 2018